# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello everyone, I'm Wang Gang.
# 前几期视频呢我用这个锅跟大家分享了怎么样去翻锅
In previous episodes I shared how to toss food with this wok.
# 当然有的粉丝说要想学一下家庭里面的小锅 用这个翻
Some fans said they want to learn how to toss food in small woks used in family settings. Use this wok.
# 然后今天我们再复习一遍这个家庭小灶的锅跟这个大锅
So today I want to review (introduce) how to toss food for both the big wok and the small one.
# 我们加两斤盐下去翻 翻给大家看一下
We'll add 2 Jin (1kg) salt (into the wok). I'll show you how to toss it.
# 好了 我们现在先复习一下上次说的锅拉到三分之一
OK. Let's review what we talked about on pulling the wok up to one third position.
# 然后下去 然后拉 下去
Then put it down. Pull up. And down.
# 第二步是下去的时候就往上面翻
Next step is to toss when pushing the wok downwards.
# 然后现在我们来讲用勺子来推这个东西
Now let's talk about how to use this ladle to push food.
# 现在我们加入盐
Now let's add in salt.
# 这里是2斤多3斤的盐 倒下去
Here we have more than 2 Jin (1kg), about 3 Jin (1.5kg) salt. Add it in.
# 然后我们就像之前的教学这样子试一下翻
Let's try tossing like this as shown in the previous tutorial.
# 翻得时候用勺子顶 把它顶出去
Use the wok spoon to push it forward when tossing.
# 回来的时候再带一下
Tip inward when it (food) comes back.
# 并不是所有的菜都适合这样子翻
Not all dishes need to be tossed like this.
# 适合这样子猛翻的只有蛋炒饭 只有炒饭类的
Only cooking egg fried rice needs this fast tossing. Only fried rice.
# 比如一些鱼的话就并不适合这样子翻
It's not suitable for cooking dishes like fish.
# 好 这个是我们的大锅翻法
Good. This is how we toss with big wok.
# 现在我们来试一下小锅
Now let's try with a small wok.
# （盐）放到这个小锅里面
Put (salt) in this small wok.
# 翻得时候锅一定要是这样子抬起来
Lift the wok above the stove like this when tossing.
# 因为家庭小灶的话 下面你这样子肯定是不行的
Because family stoves are different (smaller). It's impossible to do like this.
# 然后我们注意它的高度
Then heed the height.
# 我们平常家里面 上面就是抽油烟机
Usually we have a range hood right above the stove.
# 你拉得太高的话 这个会撞在上面
If you lift it too high, the wok will hit the range hood.
# 然后我们现在拿矮一点 这样子翻
So we now put it lower a little bit, like this.
# 并不是我们所有的菜都需要这样子去翻
Not all dishes needs tossing like this.
# 我们只坚持一个原则 需要翻得时候我们才翻
We stick to a single principle: toss only when we need to.
# 不需要翻得时候我们坚决不要去翻
Never toss if unnecessary.
# 用勺子这样子铲也可以
It's possible to just scoop like this.
# 我们这样子翻得时候一定要注意
We need to be careful when tossing.
# 注意这个火不能开得太大
Be careful not to leave the flame too strong.
# 这样一翻的话如果有水分的话锅里面会着火
Otherwise food inside may catch fire if there is steam present.
# 会发生一些危险
It can be dangerous.
# 这个是我们家庭的翻法
This is how we do "home-version" tossing.
# 然后我不建议你们手腕没有力的 拿这个翻
I don't recommend those who don't have strong arms to toss like this.
# 因为你如果没有练习过直接这样子翻得话很可能菜就翻出去了
Because it's highly likely that the food gets tossed out if you haven't practiced much.
# 大家可以买一包盐在家里面 尝试性的这样子翻一下
You can buy a bag of salt and try tossing like this.
# 好了 刚才我们看了这一些（操作）
Good. We have seen those (techniques).
# 现在我翻给你们看一下
Now let me show you how it's done.
# 然后我直接用这个锅代替我们专业灶来翻
I'll directly use this instead of the professional wok to showcase.
# 待会再这样子翻
Later I'll toss like this.
# 这是我们在专业厨房里面是这种翻法
This is how we toss in a professional kitchen.
# 然后下一个我们直接拿起来翻
Next I'll just take it up and toss.
# 你们在家里面的时候可以不用放这么多盐
You can use less salt at home.
# 就放个1斤就够了
1 Jin (0.5kg) is enough.
# 盐炒完了练习完了之后再放起来下一次可以炒菜用
After practicing, the salt can be stored and used for cooking later.
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright, that's all for this episode.